<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<content id="ws_3379427822" name="Protect Sector" author="Chem O`Dun" version="103" date="2024-12-26" save="false" description="[h1][u][u]Protect Sector[/u][/u][/h1]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;This extension allows you to protect a sector from being harassed by hostile ships.&#13;&#10;This is useful when you want to prevent hostile ships to attack your ships and stations. Or when you want to prevent from building in a sector.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2][u]Compatibility[/u][/h2]&#13;&#10;Compatible with [b]X4: Foundations 7.1[/b]. At least it written and tested with this version.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2][u]General information[/u][/h2]&#13;&#10;Always the closest possible target will be selected to attack.&#13;&#10;Several ships/fleets with one order can work in one sector.&#13;&#10;Not recommended to use single ship - the fleet is always better.&#13;&#10;[b]Mimic[/b] order in a fleet is fully supported. But, again, not set single ship to mimic mode - use the fleet instead.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2][u]Executing the order[/u][/h2]&#13;&#10;You can select the order as any other, like &quot;Protect Station&quot; or &quot;Protect Ship&quot;, from the &quot;Combat&quot; section of  orders.&#13;&#10;Please be aware - this order required the ship captain to have at least two stars in the &quot;Pilot&quot; skill.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2][u]Configuration[/u][/h2]&#13;&#10;There are a several configuration options available. You can see all of them on a screenshot.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h3][u]Home Sector[/u][/h3]&#13;&#10;This is a sector which will be protected. You can select it from the list of discovered sectors.&#13;&#10;If you select not current sector, the ship will fly to the selected sector to some &quot;safe&quot; point before to start protecting it.&#13;&#10;It can be any known sector, even if it is not yours.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h3][u]Attack Stations[/u][/h3]&#13;&#10;[b]Disabled[/b] by default.&#13;&#10;If enabled, hostile stations in the protected sector will be attacked by ship and his squad.&#13;&#10;It uses the specific logic to attack stations - equal to &quot;Coordinate Attack&quot; from the context menu.&#13;&#10;With only one exception - the syncpoint will not be created. So, all squad ships will form the similar order but will not wait for each other.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h3][u]Attack Ships[/u][/h3]&#13;&#10;You can select exact ship types:&#13;&#10;[list]&#13;&#10;[*] XL&#13;&#10;[*] L&#13;&#10;[*] M - [b]Enabled[/b] by default&#13;&#10;[*] S - [b]Enabled[/b] by default&#13;&#10;[/list]&#13;&#10;By default, the S and M ships are selected.&#13;&#10;If it will find a hostile squad - it will not be attacked, if it contains at least one ship of the type higher than highest selected one.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h3][u]Attack farther from stations[/u][/h3]&#13;&#10;There is a slider to define a minimal distance from the possible target to the hostile station. If the distance is less than the defined value, the ship will be selected as a target.&#13;&#10;If value is 0 - the distance will not be checked.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h3][u]Attack only visible targets[/u][/h3]&#13;&#10;[b]Enabled[/b] by default.&#13;&#10;Used to prevent the ship from attacking the target, which is not revealed yet or not visible for the player.&#13;&#10;It has slightly different behavior for stations and ships:&#13;&#10;- For stations - the station should be visible on a map. So - it has to be revealed, but it is not required to be in a live view, i.e. in radar range of your ships, stations, satellites, etc.&#13;&#10;- For ships - the ship should be visible online. So - it has to be in a radar range of your ships, stations, satellites, etc.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h3][u]Attack only hostile targets[/u][/h3]&#13;&#10;[b]Enabled[/b] by default.&#13;&#10;If enabled, the ship will attack only hostile targets. It will use the appropriate command to filter the targets.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h3][u]Protect our ships and stations in sector[/u][/h3]&#13;&#10;[b]Enabled[/b] by default.&#13;&#10;If enabled, the ship will react on the event when the player's ships or stations are attacked in the sector. It will try to protect them by attacking the hostile ships.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h3][u] - except military ships[/u][/h3]&#13;&#10;[b]Enabled[/b] by default.&#13;&#10;If enabled, the ship will not protect the military ships. It will not attack the hostile ships, which are attacking the military ships.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h3][u]Pursue fleeing targets[/u][/h3]&#13;&#10;[b]Disabled[/b] by default.&#13;&#10;If enabled, the ship will pursue the target, which is trying to flee after is being attacked.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h3][u]Share target with other[/u][/h3]&#13;&#10;[b]Enabled[/b] by default.&#13;&#10;If you have more than one ship or squad with the same order, you can disable this option to prevent them from attacking the same target.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h3][u]Preserve shield energy[/u][/h3]&#13;&#10;[b]Disabled[/b] by default.&#13;&#10;If enabled, the ship will not use the boosters to increase the speed. It will try to preserve the shield energy.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h3][u]Disable on destruction threat[/u][/h3]&#13;&#10;It is a percentage of hull to make this order disabled.&#13;&#10;By default, it is [b]40 percent[/b]. To disable this check - set it to 0.&#13;&#10;If set to non-zero value, the ship will stop attack and protecting when hull is less than desired percent and will try to flee.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h3][u]Park at sector core[/u][/h3]&#13;&#10;[b]Disabled[/b] by default.&#13;&#10;If enabled, the ship will try to park at the sector core, when it is not targets to fight against.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h3][u]Delay between scans, seconds[/u][/h3]&#13;&#10;Default value is [b]4 seconds[/b].&#13;&#10;If you want, you can set it between 1 and 90 seconds, with step 4 seconds. Bigger value will make less load on the CPU...&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h3][u]Record to logbook[/u][/h3]&#13;&#10;[b]Enabled[/b] by default.&#13;&#10;If enabled, the ship will record the events to the logbook. I.e. starts, travel to desired sector, flying to the target, attacking the target, destroying the target, etc.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2][u]Situation when nothing to attack[/u][/h2]&#13;&#10;If no Attack target is selected (i.e. no station and no any ship types are selected) - the ship's captain will periodically call to the player to inform about absence of the order.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2][u]Special Thanks[/u][/h2]&#13;&#10;Special thanks to the pilot [url=https://steamcommunity.com/profiles/76561198087933619/myworkshopfiles/?appid=392160]Assailer[/url] for his awesome script [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2458720435]&quot;Sector Patrol&quot;[/url] which was used as a base for this one.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2][u]Links[/u][/h2]&#13;&#10;There is a thread on EgoSoft forum - [url=https://forum.egosoft.com/viewtopic.php?p=5257237][Mod/AIScript] Order &quot;Protect Sector&quot;[/url]" lastupdate="1735242027">
  <text language="7" name="Protect Sector" description="Protect Sector against hostile ships"></text>
  <text language="33" name="Protéger le Secteur" description="Protéger le Secteur contre les vaisseaux hostiles"></text>
  <text language="34" name="Proteger el Sector" description="Proteger el Sector contra naves hostiles"></text>
  <text language="39" name="Proteggi Settore" description="Proteggi Settore contro navi ostili"></text>
  <text language="44" name="Protect Sector" description="Protect Sector against hostile ships"></text>
  <text language="49" name="Sektor schützen" description="Sektor gegen feindliche Schiffe schützen"></text>
  <text language="86" name="保护区域" description="保护区域免受敌对舰船的攻击"></text>
  <text language="88" name="সেক্টর রক্ষা করুন" description="শত্রু জাহাজের বিরুদ্ধে সেক্টর রক্ষা করুন"></text>
  <text language="380" name="Захист сектора" description="Захистити сектор від ворожих кораблів"></text>
</content>
