<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<content
  id="ws_3379427822"
  name="Protect Sector"
  author="Chem O`Dun"
  version="109"
  date="2025-05-18"
  save="false"
  description="This extension allows you to protect a sector from being harassed by hostile ships.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2][b]Compatibility[/b][/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;Compatible with [b]X4: Foundations 7.10[/b] and upper. At least it written and tested with versions [b]7.10[/b] and [b]7.50[/b].&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2][b]Features[/b][/h2]&#13;&#10;[list]&#13;&#10;[*] Always the closest possible target will be selected to attack.&#13;&#10;[*] Several ships/fleets with one order can work in one sector or crossed sectors.&#13;&#10;[*] Not recommended to use single ship - the fleet is always better.&#13;&#10;[*] [b]Mimic[/b] order in a fleet is fully supported. But, again, not set single ship to mimic mode - use the fleet instead.&#13;&#10;[*] The [b]Lost Ship Replacement[/b] feature of version [b]7.50[/b] is fully supported.&#13;&#10;[*] The own ([b]experimental[/b]) order for station attacks is available.&#13;&#10;[*] The workaround for player ships repairing/restocking not only in current sector is implemented.&#13;&#10;[*] From version [b]1.08[/b] have own icons for the [b]Protect Sector[/b] and [b]Station attack[/b] orders.&#13;&#10;[/list]&#13;&#10;[h2][b]Download[/b][/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;In addition you can do it via the [url=https://www.nexusmods.com/x4foundations/mods/1566]Nexus Mods[/url]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2][b]Executing the order[/b][/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;You can select the order as any other, like &quot;Protect Station&quot; or &quot;Protect Ship&quot;, from the &quot;Combat&quot; section of  orders.&#13;&#10;Please be aware - this order requires the ship captain to have at least [b]two stars[/b] in the &quot;Pilot&quot; skill.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2][b]Configuration[/b][/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;There are a several configuration options available. You can see all of them on a screenshot.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2]Home Sector[/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;This is a sector which will be protected. You can select it from the list of discovered sectors.&#13;&#10;If you select not current sector, the ship will fly to the selected sector to some &quot;safe&quot; point before to start protecting it.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;It can be any known sector, even if it is not yours.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2]Attack Stations[/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b]Disabled[/b] by default.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;If enabled, hostile stations in the protected sector will be attacked by ship and his squad.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h3][b]Use &quot;Coordinate attack&quot;[/b][/h3]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b]Enabled[/b] by default.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;If enabled, the ship will use the &quot;Coordinate Attack&quot; order to attack the stations. It will be used for the stations only, not for the ships.&#13;&#10;If disabled, the ship will use the usual &quot;Attack&quot; order to attack the stations.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h3][b]Use experimental &quot;Attack Station&quot;[/b][/h3]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b]Disabled[/b] by default.&#13;&#10;If enabled, the ship will use the experimental &quot;Attack Station&quot; order to attack the stations. It will be used for the stations only, not for the ships.&#13;&#10;Will work only if the ships in a fleet has [b]L[/b] or [b]XL[/b] classes only. Otherwise, the order will be ignored, and selection from previous parameter will be used.&#13;&#10;For [b]L[/b] only - four and more ships are recommended.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h3][u]Important notice[/u][/h3]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;If Use experimental &quot;Attack Station&quot; selected, the ship will use the [b]experimental[/b] order independently of the order type selected in the previous parameter.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2]Attack Ships[/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;You can select exact ship types:&#13;&#10;[list]&#13;&#10;[*] XL&#13;&#10;[*] L&#13;&#10;[*] M&#13;&#10;[*] S&#13;&#10;[/list]&#13;&#10;By default are set depending on the player ship type.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;If it will find a hostile squad - it will not be attacked, if it contains at least one ship of the type higher than highest selected one.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2]Attack farther from stations[/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;There is a slider to define a minimal distance from the possible target to the hostile station. If the distance is less than the defined value, the ship will be selected as a target.&#13;&#10;If value is 0 - the distance will not be checked.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;Default value is [b]0[/b].&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2]Attack only visible targets[/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b]Enabled[/b] by default.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;Used to prevent the ship from attacking the target, which is not revealed yet or not visible for the player.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;It has slightly different behavior for stations and ships:&#13;&#10;[list]&#13;&#10;[*] For stations - the station should be visible on a map. So - it has to be revealed, but it is not required to be in a live view, i.e. in radar range of your ships, stations, satellites, etc.&#13;&#10;[*] For ships - the ship should be visible online. So - it has to be in a radar range of your ships, stations, satellites, etc.&#13;&#10;[/list]&#13;&#10;[h2]Attack only hostile targets[/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b]Enabled[/b] by default.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;If enabled, the ship will attack only hostile targets. It will use the appropriate command to filter the targets.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2]By negative relation[/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;This is a slider to define the relation to the [b]Player[/b]. Take in account - relation is shown as [b]positive[/b] value, due to limitation of the game engine.&#13;&#10;So, if you want to attack the ships with relation [b]-10[/b] and lower - you have to set the value to [b]10[/b].&#13;&#10;Default value is [b]25[/b], i.e. attack the ships with relation [b]-25[/b] and lower.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;Please take in account -  when previous parameter is enabled, you can set this one in between 25 and 30 (-25 and -30 relation).&#13;&#10;If the [b]Attack only hostile targets[/b] is disabled - the value can be set in between 0 and 30 (0 and -30 relation).&#13;&#10;[b]Use it carefully.[/b]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2]Protect our ships and stations in sector[/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b]Enabled[/b] by default.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;If enabled, the ship will react on the event when the player's ships or stations are attacked in the sector. It will try to protect them by attacking the hostile ships.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2]- except military ships[/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b]Enabled[/b] by default.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;If enabled, the ship will not protect the military ships. It will not attack the hostile ships, which are attacking the military ships.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2]Pursue fleeing targets[/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b]Disabled[/b] by default.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;If enabled, the ship will pursue the target, which is trying to flee after is being attacked.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2]Share target with other[/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b]Enabled[/b] by default.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2]Attack distance: percentage of radar range[/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;This setting allows you to define the ship behavior when the target is identified and selected.&#13;&#10;The attack de facto contains two stages:&#13;&#10;[list]&#13;&#10;[*] The ship is trying to reach the target till some acceptable distance. This distance is defined as a percentage of the radar range.&#13;&#10;[*] The ship is trying to attack the target when it is in the acceptable distance.&#13;&#10;[/list]&#13;&#10;[h2]Avoid boosters usage[/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b]Disabled[/b] by default.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2]Disable on destruction threat[/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;It is a percentage of hull of the target to make this order disabled. Useful when you want to achieve more abandoned ships.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;By default, it is [b]0 percent[/b] - i.e. disabled this check.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;If set to non-zero value, the ship will stop attacking when hull is less than desired percent.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2]Park at sector core[/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b]Disabled[/b] by default.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;If enabled, the ship will try to park at the sector core, when it is not targets to fight against.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2]Park exactly there[/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;It's [b]optional[/b] parameter, it means - it can be skipped to set.&#13;&#10;Moreover, if you want to park exactly at same position - disable the [b]Park at sector core[/b] option.&#13;&#10;To set the value of this parameter - you have to select the exact position on the galaxy map inside the appropriate sector.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[h2]Delay between scans, seconds[/h2]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;Default value is [b]4 seconds[/b].&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;### Ignore the threats of Hazardous zones&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;`Disabled` by default.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;From version 1.08 `Protect Sector` order will automatically finished in such sectors. Appropriate message will be shown in the logbook.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;If you still want to use this order in the hazardous zone - you can enable this option. But please be aware - the ships can be destroyed in the hazardous zone.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;### Record to logbook&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;`Enabled` by default.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;If enabled, the ship will record the events to the logbook. I.e. starts, travel to desired sector, flying to the target, attacking the target, destroying the target, etc.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;## Special Thanks&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;To the pilot [Assailer](https://steamcommunity.com/profiles/76561198087933619/myworkshopfiles/?appid=392160) for his awesome script [&quot;Sector Patrol&quot;](https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2458720435).&#13;&#10;"
  lastupdate="">
  <text language="7" name="Protect Sector" description="Protect Sector against hostile ships"></text>
  <text language="33" name="Protéger le Secteur" description="Protéger le Secteur contre les vaisseaux hostiles"></text>
  <text language="34" name="Proteger el Sector" description="Proteger el Sector contra naves hostiles"></text>
  <text language="39" name="Proteggi Settore" description="Proteggi Settore contro navi ostili"></text>
  <text language="44" name="Protect Sector" description="Protect Sector against hostile ships"></text>
  <text language="49" name="Sektor schützen" description="Sektor gegen feindliche Schiffe schützen"></text>
  <text language="86" name="保护区域" description="保护区域免受敌对舰船的攻击"></text>
  <text language="88" name="সেক্টর রক্ষা করুন" description="শত্রু জাহাজের বিরুদ্ধে সেক্টর রক্ষা করুন"></text>
  <text language="380" name="Захист сектора" description="Захистити сектор від ворожих кораблів"></text>
  <dependency version="710"></dependency>
</content>